Salman **Ashraf**



Manchester, England 🏫

+44 7440 156586

Salman.ashraf2513@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/salman-ashraf2513 in



← Visit my website to read more about me •

I am a confident communicator with experience in customer assistant roles and retail. I have welldeveloped language skills and expertise in computerized systems. I am hardworking and motivated with a positive mindset and proactive approaches to achieve the company's targets in an efficient and timely fashion. I am happy to work as part of a team, but also use my initiative when necessary. I work well under pressure, and I can deal with changes and unexpected events. I am available for an immediate start.

Professional Experience

OCTOBER 2020 - PRESENT

Customer Service Assistant/Tesco Extra, Gorton, Manchester

Whilst at Tesco, I was able to obtain a variety of skills while helping the team. In a short amount of time, I've gained confidence in talking to customers and assisting them. It was of my main responsibilities to address customers' inquiries and concerns. Time management is the key at Tesco because I had to maintain knowledge of products while keeping track of promotions and providing excellent customer service. Working with customers tough me how customers will use the company's products to achieve their goals and I can use this knowledge in the sales and marketing industry.

SEPTEMBER 2019 – JUNE 2020

Customer Service Assistant / Wilko, Walthamstow, London

During my stay in this company, I was primarily responsible for the promotion area of the workplace. My role was to learn and sell products that were initially on promotion while providing highly satisfying customer service. Helping and solving problems were the key skills I obtained during the work. I usually worked within a team, but I was also trusted for doing individual tasks that required communication and awareness. Once I got enough experience, I was able to share my knowledge with new starters.

Leadership Experience

FEBRUARY 2021 - MAY 2021

Peer Mentoring for Mathematics and Physics/ The Manchester College

As a mentor, I was able to establish an honest and respectful relationship with my students and provide support, guidance, and feedback to obtain desired outcomes. I always tried to be friendly, and I made my students believe that they have the necessary skills and experience to achieve their goals. I made a genuine commitment to mentoring while I had to manage my own education. With some long working days and excellent time management, I was able to accomplish my aim.

Education

CURRENT INSTITUTE

BSc Computer Science/The University of Manchester

This course is based on the development of new programs in science and engineering. It will provide me with the skills needed to contribute to the rapidly growing computing fields. The course aims to equip the students with the logic behind programming, explain different aspects of software, and introduce finance instruments. This content is delivered across 3 years.

SEPTEMBER 2020 – JULY 2021

Access to Engineering/The Manchester College

The focus of this course is based around the science and engineering industry. I studied different level 3 units in Mathematics, Physics, and Electronics. I also learned other units focusing on the use of MS office, processing programs, spreadsheets, and other ICT techniques. My final mark for the course was 144 UCAS points.

JULY 2020

GCSEs/Barking & Dagenham, London

GCSEs level 2 course. Final grades:

- Mathematics: A*
- Combined Science (Physics, Chemistry, Biology): A*
- English: BStatistics: C

MARCH 2021

SIA Door Supervisor License/SBC, Manchester

The course is arranged in 4 units:

- Unit 1 is about understanding the principle of working in the security industry.
- Unit 2 is about working as a door supervisor.
- Unit 3 explains the application of conflict management.
- Unit 4 simulates the use of physical intervention.

Additional

- o Languages: Fluent in English, Italian, Urdu, Hindi, and Punjabi.
- o Technical Skills: Web development knowledge (HTML, CSS), MS Office
- o **Interests:** Football, cricket, driving, and music.